<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Stuart M. Davis - Polymath - Blog</title><link href="http://www.polymathist.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.polymathist.me/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.polymathist.me/</id><updated>2018-06-29T22:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Rebuilding My Web Presence</title><link href="http://www.polymathist.me/blog/2018/06/29/rebuilding-web-presence/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-29T22:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-29T22:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Stuart Davis</name></author><id>tag:www.polymathist.me,2018-06-29:/blog/2018/06/29/rebuilding-web-presence/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just took a stroll through the &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/"&gt;wayback machine&lt;/a&gt; to get a sense at how long I've been at this from a website perspective. As far as I can tell one of main properties was stood up around 2002 where I used a cutting edge flash animation as my main navigation feature. The next major revamp after that included an archive of various doodles and a decent set of reviews regarding the cigars that I had endured. More on that some other time...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Wayback and back again&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just took a stroll through the &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/"&gt;wayback machine&lt;/a&gt; to get a sense at how long I've been at this from a website perspective. As far as I can tell one of main properties was stood up around 2002 where I used a cutting edge flash animation as my main navigation feature. The next major revamp after that included an archive of various doodles and a decent set of reviews regarding the cigars that I had endured. More on that some other time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't stop with the one site as I felt the need to maintain different levels of decorum on different properties. My mind was constantly bouncing around between a blog filled with personal rants on the universe, a site dedicated to pursuing enhanced levels of business acumen, a collaboration focused on classical music, and so on and so forth. Sites popped up around me with the hope that could regularly rotate through the media empire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas... my focus shifted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my. I hadn't been on twitter for some time but just a quick dose helps me to realize that it's interesting to recognize your past vices and interests but that it's important to trim the fat to meet your current needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pelican&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that I want to create a site but I want to do it on the cheap as much as possible. A friend has been working through a Pelican static site hosted on github and I think that is going to be the best option. There are a lot of things to figure out about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across a decent article/tutorial &lt;a href="https://appliedcaffeine.org/navbaritems.html" title="Applied Caffeine - Pelican navbar menu items"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; regarding the implementation of custom menu items in the navigation bar and that lead me to initial adopting the &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes/tree/master/pelican-bootstrap3" title="bootstrap3 on github"&gt;bootstrap3&lt;/a&gt; theme as a starting point for the site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="process"></category><category term="approach"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry></feed>